

NADEEM MEMON

BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT MANAGER

SUMMARY:

To seek a passionate career in the field of Business development & Sales and to channelize my working ability in order to be associated with organization & reaching its vision & goals, proving to be an asset for the company.

SKILLS & EXPERTISE:

Knowledge for selling IT software solutions and products Mobile & Web app development,
Learning management system

Content development Level 1-2-3 ADDIE Rules Gamification

CRM

ΑI

SAAS

Salesforce

CMS LXP

I.T Hardware Cache box, WIFI, Nutanix

SKILLS AND STRENGTHS

Persistent
Result-oriented
Critical thinking
Value selling
Effective communication
Data Analysis
Customer relationship building

CAREER SUMMARY:

WORKED AS A LEAD BUSINESS CONSULTANT PRESALES WITH LEARNINGMATE SOLUTIONS FROM FEB 2023 TILL SEPT 2023

WORKED AS A SR EDUCATION CONSULTANT WITH TRAINOCATE INDIA FROM MAR2022 TILL MAR JAN 2023

WORKED AS A BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT MANAGER WITH HORIZZON TECHNOLOGIES MAR 2021 TILL FEB 2022

WORKED WITH SHEZAR TECH AS A BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT MANAGER JANUARY 2015 TILL MAR 2021

WORKED WITH COLVILL BANKS AS A RESEARCHER & PROFILER - SEPTEMBER 2013 TILL DECEMBER 2014.

WORKED WITH TCS E-SERVE PVT LTD AS SR. CUSTOMER SERVICE REPRESENTATIVE & UP-SELLING - FEB 2008 TILL AUGUST 2013.

WORKED WITH ZENTA PVT LTD AS SALES REPRESENTATIVE - JULY 2006 TILL JANUARY

EDUCATION

B.COM GRADUATE FROM THE UNIVERSITY OF MUMBAI - CLASS OF 2006.

CONTACT INFORMATION:

Phone: +91 9833 767 707

Email: nadeemmemon1985@yahoo.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/inadeem-memon

PERSONAL INFO:

Dob: 27th May 1985

Location Jogeshwari, Mumbai, Maharashtra. Marital status - Married

AWARDS AND RECOGNITION

Awarded as Employee of month OCT 2019

Achieved Topaz award for Best Customer Service in TCS E-Serve Pvt Ltd

Certified as Best Agent for Sales Performance in Zenta Pvt Ltd.

WORK JOURNEY:

LEARNINGMATE SOLUTIONS

- Working across all phases of Business Development i.e. Qualification of Opportunity, SolutionDiscussion, Pricing, Orals, Due Diligence, and Contract Negotiation.
- Creating the proposal schedule and deciding on roles and responsibilities for team members.
- Defining and owning the bid response process starting from RFI/ RFP receipt to submission and defense including Setting up a process for bid defense.
- Owning and leading bid management for all RFI/RFP responses including managing the bid response team and independent bid review team.
- Finalizing the structure of the response with clear timelines.
- Interact with management personnel and facilitate appropriate reviews for smoother submission of proposal.
- ·Maintaining a continuous feedback loop to ensure that learning from each bid is captured and appliedin subsequent bid

TRAINOCATE INDIA

Leading the Trainocate Delivery team that manages the Education Services Delivery lifecyclefor Cloud and Automation Portfolio Enablement & End Customer Education & Certification. Successfully deliveredAWS, Microsoft, GoogleCloud, IBM and, UI Path skills for major DQ clients, partners, and at specified Net PromoterScore (NPS).

- The role involves Implementation skills for end-users
- Technical accreditation and certification
- Support for channel programs &initiatives
- LMS implementation and content sourcing.
- Sales Activities Develop overall curriculum/content, customizations, assessments, roadmaps and competency plans for client audiences

HORIZZON TECHNOLOGIES

- Spearheading the entire spectrum of business development functions pertaining to pre- sales, sales & marketing initiatives globally to upsurge revenue generation and increase the overall sales of the company's product & services.
- Leading the Sales, Pre-Sales, and Business Development functions in the PAN India, EMEA, and APAC region.
- Responsible for the revenue generation and sales numbers from these regions. Fostering the sales of high-value propositions through the successful acquisition of global customers.
- Meeting the prospective customers, proficiently gathering & analyzing requirements, interpreting their needs, presenting & demonstrating products/services, adopting a solution selling approach, and proactively providing them with a derivation of advice for prospective products or services that are aligned with the customers' demands.
- Handling key account management of premium and strategic customers(Tata Power, Sharekhan by BNP Paribas, Mahindra Partners, Quick Heal, Wondechef, Murugappa, CARE Ratings, and KIMS Hospitals, to name a few) Maximizing the revenue upsurge from the new and existing accounts through upselling and cross-selling.
- Managing complete bid management process, including attending the pre-bid meetings, responses to RFP,RFI, EOI, PPQ, ITT and RFQ, etc.,
- Ability to build, liaison, and maintain beneficial business relationships with all the enterprise accounts and their vertical heads, CxOs, directors, and key Decision-makers.

SHEZARTECH

Working as business development manager for INDIA and UAE clients to generate lead in B2B/B2C Sales working closely with President for E-Learning services and software product deals.

Providing detailed information for E-Learning services and IT software solutions for training and development to offshore and outsource with Shezar.

Dealing in solutions like Mobile app and Web app development, Learning Management System, PING Field force management app, Content development, gamification, analytics.

Arranging call/office meeting for further discussion and deal closure.

Dealing with CEO and higher level professionals to interact and close details after understanding their needs and building good relations across in international market.

Projects - Digitalizednow, BI worldwide, IOPEX, DR Reddy, Amazon, Emerging market, Neosoft technologies, MPS ltd

SHEZAR TECHNOLOGIES

Working as business development manager for INDIA, AUSTRALIA, UAE, USA & UK clients to generate lead in appropriate sector for IT software services and solutions and closing deal along with President.

Providing detailed information for IT software solutions in different industries Retail, FMCG, Automobile, BFSI, Education management. IT and others

Dealing in solutions like Mobile app and Web app development, LMS, Content development, gamification, analytics, ERP, CRM, CMS.

Dealing with CEO and higher level professionals to interact and close deals after understanding their needs and building good relations across in Domestic as well as in International market.

Projects - LRI Education, designing digitally, practice labs ,learning curve, Bestseller, Godrej, Bajaj finsery, Mastek, P&G

COLVILL BANKS AS A RESEARCHER & PROFILER

Researching, Sourcing & Screening Corporate Candidates for APAC & Middle East region.

Interacting with Clients in Singapore & Australia.

Bringing new ideas to give appropriate information within the time frame.

Providing training to new recruits regarding Screening & Smart research.

Maintaining company's standard with the client.

TCS E-SERVE PVT LTD

Interacting with Credit Counseling Agencies & Clients in United States of America for payment arrangement plan.

Understanding & Resolving Customer queries related to Payment arrangement plan.

Reviewing the daily performance of the team.

Maintaining AHT tracker of the team.

Helping team members to achieve their goals & targets.

Providing training to new recruits regarding the process & Customer Service Skills and up-selling of debt relief plan for U.S Citi Bank customers

ZENTA PVT LTD

Handling customer's issues related to Credit Cards with 3 major airlines of United States.

Selling Chase Credit Cards to frequent flyers.

Assisted customers with their Credit Card Payments.

Dealt with multiple types of Customer Queries.

Explaining Customers about rewards & miles with detailed product knowledge.

Retain customers with customized offers.

Maintained high quality standards.

TRAINING ATTENDED:

Attended internal Sales training in Zenta Pvt ltd.

Attended internal Customer Service training in TCS.

Kind Regards, NADEEM.M